Hello and welcome back. Active contours, also called snakes, are
大家好 欢迎回来 主动轮廓 也称Snakes   【字幕未完成】
very important in image and video processing.
在图像和视频处理中非常重要
They appear in a number of commercial products and they are very useful for
它们出现在很多商品中 同时也大量应用于图像与视频分割技术
numerous image and video segmentation. Let me illustrate the basic concept
现在来讲解一下主动轮廓的基本概念
behind active contours. The idea is that you start from one or
其思路就是从一或多个曲线开始
multiple curves. For example, I'm going to draw a curve
例如 在这朵花周围画一曲线
that surrounds the flower, which is my object of interest.
这是我们感兴趣的目标 (区域)
And the basic idea behind active contours is to design velocities that will move
主动轮廓的基本概念就是设计这个曲线的速度 使其朝向花朵移动
this curve towards the flower. Hopefully, as the curve moves, it's going
随着曲线移动 它最终会在这朵花的边缘上停止
to end up in the border of the flower. So, we need basically to design
所以我们需要构思一种速度
velocities that will move any initial contour towards the contour of interest,
能够使任意初始轮廓都移向目标轮廓
which is the boundary of the object of interest.
也就是感兴趣目标的边界
Now, I can write down, the formulation for this and the equations for this, but
现在 我可以写下相应的公式和方程式
I think it's better if we first learn the material that is coming next week, as a
但是我觉得如果学习了下周的课程
back ground, and that will help us to write this in a much, much elegan, form.
以此为背景 再给出公式效果会更好 而且有助我们写得更讲究
So, this week, instead of writing down the exact weight
因此 这一周 我们不给出主动轮廓的确切定义
of active counters, I'm going to just illustrate you some
而是举出几个例子给大家
examples to motivate you and get you very excited to learn the background, material
令你们对下周要学习的课程背景、材料更感兴趣
that we're going to learn next week. So, let's go and watch some movies with
好了 现在一起来看看一些与主动轮廓有关的视频
examples of active contour, inside the image processing online
在图像处理的在线包里
package and inside Adobe's Photoshop. So, let's just observe that right now.
和Adobe的Photoshop里都有涉及 那么 现在立即来看看
In order to illustrate one of the examples of active contours, we're going
为了举出主动轮廓的其中一个例子
to be using, again, the image processing online website where, as we have seen
我们准备再次使用之前看过的图像处理在线网站
before, there is many very interesting image processing algorithms implemented.
里面实现了很多非常有趣的图像处理算法
And particularly, now, we are in the Chan-Vese webpage,
特别地 我们现在位于 Chan-Vese 的页面
which is an implementation of one of the approaches for active contours developed
这是主动轮廓的各种方法的其中一个实现
by Tony Chan and Luminita Vese. Before we show you one of the examples
是由Tony Chan和Luminita Vese发展而来的 在把这个例子的实时运行展示给大家看之前
running actually in real time, let's just basically run the demo provided by the
我们先来运行这个网站的编者提供的演示样本
author of this website. So here, we see contours evolving.
那么 在这里 我们看到轮廓的演变
This is a very clear example of a contour evolving towards the segment.
这是一个非常清晰的例子 轮廓向着分割区域演变
Here, we have another one, just look at this one.
这里 我们又有另外一个 先看看这个
And here, we see once again, how contours are evolving and yet once again.
然后这里 我们再一次看到 轮廓是怎样变化的 再看一遍
So, that's a basic idea of active contour. This was a very fast video, just
因此 这就是主动轮廓的基本概念 这是个非常快的视频
to illustrate one of the examples. But let's just run one, so we're going to
只是图解说明了一个个例子 不过我们还是来运行一个
have more time, to look at it. Wwe're going to run the demo online as we have
让我们有更多时间去观察它 我们要运行这个在线的演示
done in the past for other algorithms. I'm going to pick this, example, it's
以前演示其他算法的时候我们也这样做过 我会选取这个作为例子
just one example, I'm not going to change the parameters, we don't know exactly
这仅仅是一个例子 我不准备改变这个参数
since we haven't discussed the technique, what this parameter means, so I'm going
因为我们还没讨论到这个技术 所以大家还不清楚这个参数具体指什么
to just, leave the default and I'm going to run it.
所以 我们保留默认值 然后来运行它
Remember, now is rhyming as we see here, but it's rhyming in the server wrap that
记住 这里我们看到 现在算法正在运行 不过是在服务器端运行
is provided by the imaging processing online.
运行过程是在线的图像处理服务器进行的
The algorithm is actually much, much faster, than we can see, it actually can
这个算法实际上比我们看到的快很多很多
be run on real time, but it's run on the server.
它其实可以即时运行 但这是在服务器上运行
And here is the result. We see once again, the initial contours,
这个就是结果 我们再来看一遍 这个初始轮廓
these intial contours at the very beginning are the initial contours and
最开始的这些蓝色轮廓就是的初始轮廓
then, we see the boundaries. The curves have evolved toward those
然后我们看到了边界 这些曲线已经向边界变化
boundaries. The curves have evolved to segment out
这些曲线已经演变成包络着目标物体的分割线
the object of interest. There are some spurious objects and we
这里有一些伪目标
are going to understand why they happen, but mostly, it has done a great job
我们将来会搞明白它们形成的原因 但总体上 就寻找这朵花的边界而言
basically, in finding the boundary of the flower, which is probably the object of
这完成得已经很不错了 这里花朵就是本图像中我们感兴趣的目标
interest for this image. And we see once again, these contours
我们再看一遍这些轮廓的变化
evolving. And this is, as I say, something that
这就是 像我提过的 会下周学到的知识
we're going to learn next week. Exactly the formulas, exactly the math
特别是其中的公式 和背后的数学原理
behind it. But this illustrates the idea.
但是这个例子可以说明这个概念
Thank you for this part of the video. It's now time to illustrate using Adobe
感谢收看这部分视频 现在开始用Adobe Photoshop
Photoshop one implementation of active contours.
演示主动轮廓的一种实现方式
In particular, we're going to be using this tool in active contours that is a
特别地 我们准备在主动轮廓中用这个工具
selection tool and look what's going to happen.
这是个选择性工具 一起来看看效果
Please observe my mouse. Look how I'm moving the mouse and the
请仔细注意我的光标 看看我是怎样移动光标
contours are being automatically attracted to the boundary of the flower.
使轮廓自动向花朵的边界靠拢
You know, how I just clicked and it's basically catching the flower.
我是怎样仅仅靠点击就捕捉到花朵的呢
I almost didn't move my mouse, I just click inside the object of interest, and
我几乎没有移动我的光标 我只是点击目标图像内部
we capture the flower. Let me do that again here. I'm going to
然后就捕捉到这朵花了 我们这里再来做一次
just click and it's capturing this part of the flower.
我只点击这里 就捕捉到花朵的这一部分了
So, you see how we can help, and we have already learned about user interaction by
所以 你看到 我们是怎么做到的 而且我们已经学过用户交互
doing a few clicks inside the flower. Basically, a technique related to active
通过在花朵内部的几次点击 一种与主动轮廓相关的技术
contours, move my clicks towards the boundaries of the object of interest.
就从我点击的位置出发 最终将分割曲线移向感兴趣目标的边界
This is a very, very interesting technique,
这是一项非常非常有趣的技术
this time, implemented inside Adobe Photoshop.
这次 在Adobe Photoshop中实现
And this provides in our demo of active contour type of approaches.
同时也提供了几种实现主动轮廓的演示样本
Thank you. These examples that we just saw should
谢谢 这些我们刚才看到的例子
motivate you for the material that is coming next week.
应该可以对大家下周的课程产生促进作用
Before we go into that, we have a couple of additional and very, very exciting
在此之前 我们还有一些附加的很有趣的东西
things to learn about video segmentation. So, I see you in the next video.
来帮助学习视频分割 因此 下个视频再见
Thank you.
谢谢大家